Alright everyone, please take your seats.
Okay, class begins now.
In this video I'd like to briefly introduce to you
various animals in a simple and enjoyable manner.
I'd like everyone to be able to watch,
therefore almost all pictures were drawn by myself.
With that said, some parts may be somewhat unclear.
but I hope you can enjoy my class.
Well then, today
we'll look into Tagame(Kirkaldyia deyrolli).
(Kirkaldyia deyrolli: A species of giant water bugs.)
How much do you know about Tagame?
Tagame is a kind of Kamemushi
(stink bugs/shield bugs),
and its name means 'stink bug living in a paddy'
(Ta + Kame(paddy + stink bug))
That's all it means
Tagame
Many of you must have heard the name,
but likely only few have seen it in person.
Well, these days the number of Tagame
is sharply decreasing.
But you see, Tagame and Gengoro (diving beetles) got
the title of the strongest bugs in the rice fields.
Tagame belongs to the Kamemushi (Hemiptera) order.
THe Kamemushi order mainly split into 2 groups:
terrestrial and aquatic
That one stinky bug that everyone must be familiar with
belongs to the former group.
Cicadas also belong to this group.
In the aquatic group Amenbo(water strider) and
Kooimushi (Appasus) are the notable ones.
Unlike the terrestrial group, the aquatic group bugs
aren't known for their stench.
Everyone, do you know what the Amenbo (water strider) originates from?
Fu Fu
Tick Tick Tick Tick Tick Tick Tick ...
Right, Amenbo originates from 'smells like a candy'
(ame no you)
Sometimes people also compare the Tagame's smell
to banana or even mint
Now what does the Tagame eat?
Tagame and many other aquatic Kamemushi are carnivores.
Amenbo eats small bugs that fall to the water surface,
but Tagame is called the 'Ruler of the Paddies'.
That's because ...
It ambushes its preys from inside the water,
And dines on anything small enough for it to catch.
It mainly eats frogs and fish,
sometimes other bugs and even snakes!
Tagame's mouse is shaped like a straw.
This is called 'Koufun'(proboscis).
After catching prey with its sickle-like front legs,
It stabs its mouse, Koufun, and then
transfer poison and digestive juice through it.
At first the captured prey struggles to escape,
but gradually becomes paralysed by the poison.
With that done, Tagame begins to liquefy
the prey's innards,
and sucks the digested innards, like drinking from a straw.
That's why once Tagame finishes with its meal,
only skin and bones remain of it.
Teacher, I have a question! Since it lives inside the water does it mean Tagame cannot fly?
(Trying her best to make a high-piched voice)
Mhhm, I see, you may well think so.
Trust is, Tagame is a professional when it comes to flying as well!
It comes out of the water and, while its wings
are spread, it moves its legs around in preparation.
It often flies when during breeding season or when moving to another home.
Research results showed that the same individuals were
identified at opposite spots of a 7km mountain.
Isn't it a little scary thinking that such an infamous bug can also fly.
I'm also afraid.
Teacher, it is said that Tagame is
an endangered species,
how comes such a powerful critter is facing extinction?
(Trying her best to make a cool-guy voice)
Mm-hmm
That's a good question.
Tagame, as its name suggests, has deep relationship
with man-made paddies.
But people began to use pesticides
to create higher quality rice yields.
Due to that, Tagame and other paddy-dwelling bugs numbers started to whittle down.
Additionally, a new method, called Kanden(乾田),
for growing rice more efficiently has appeared.
With Kanden, rice fields are separated
from the water path,
and farmers can now completely dry it
by controling the water flow as they like.
This results in an environment that paddy-dwelling bugs can't survive in.
Which means Tagame has nothing to eat.
When people evolve for their own sake
other life forms end up suffering in result.
However! However, in order to prevent the extinction of Tagame and other species,
activities to create paddies that these species can live in were created.
I hope we can create an environment where we can better live in symbiosis with other animals.
Well, that's enough stydying for today.
It'd bring me joy if you learnt something
about Tagame today.
If you don't mind, please subscribe to my channel
and follow me on Twitter.
Well then, let's meet again in another lesson.
Have a nice day, everyone.